Egor Lyfar, Programmer

egor.lyfar@gmail.com | (912) 555-4321 | San Francisco, California, US

SoundCloud: https://soundcloud.example.com/dandymusicnl

.....

SUMMARY

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinal!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

EDUCATION

University of Oklahoma

2011-06-01 — 2014-01-01

Bachelor - Information Technology

SKILLS

Web Development (Master): HTML, CSS, Javascript

Compression (Master): Mpeg, MP4, GIF

.....

EXPERIENCE

Pied Piper | CEO/President

2013-12-01 — 2014-12-01

http://piedpiper.example.com

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman ScoresTM that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

PUBLICATIONS

Video compression for 3d media

Oct 1, 2014

Hooli

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silicon_Valley_(TV_series)

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

PROJECTS

Miss Direction | Smoogle | Team lead, Designer missdirection.example.com

2016-08-24 — 2016-08-24

A mapping engine that misguides you

- Won award at AIHacks 2016
- Built by all women team of newbie programmers
- Using modern technologies such as GoogleMaps, Chrome Extension and Javascript

AWARDS

Digital Compression Pioneer Award

2014-11-01

There is no spoon.	
VOLUNTEERING	
Teacher CoderDojo	2012-01-01 — 2013-01-01
http://coderdojo.example.com/	
Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.	
• Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'	
LANGUAGES	
English (Native speaker)	
INTERESTS	
INTERESTS Wildlife [Ferrets , Unicorns]	
Wildlife [Ferrets , Unicorns]	onsultant for Main St. Company
Wildlife [Ferrets , Unicorns] REFERENCES	onsultant for Main St. Company